<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Command-Line-Foo on anthony lukach</title><link>https://alukach.com/tags/command-line-foo/</link><description>Recent content in Command-Line-Foo on anthony lukach</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alukach.com/tags/command-line-foo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>pushd and popd forever</title><link>https://alukach.com/posts/pushd-all-day-long/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alukach.com/posts/pushd-all-day-long/</guid><description>Becoming tired of typing paths repeatedly in the terminal, I realized that I should be using pushd and popd to be navigating directory structures. For those uninitiated, pushd changes your current directory in a similar fashion to cd but additionally adds the former directory to a stack. You can later return to the former directory by executing popd, popping it from the directory history. Unfortunately, the commands pushd and popd both require at least twice as many characters to type as cd and additionally come with the overhead of having to learnt o use a new command instead of something that is nearly instinctual.</description></item><item><title>SSH Port Forwarding</title><link>https://alukach.com/posts/ssh-port-forwarding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alukach.com/posts/ssh-port-forwarding/</guid><description>The other week I found myself up at 2am in Canada setting up a VPN between my home computer (running Ubuntu) in Seattle and my laptop &amp;lt;partyhard.jpg&amp;gt;. I had enabled SSH access on my home computer and had set up port forwarding on my router to allow for access from the outside world ahead of time, but had forgotten that I would need to have a port forwarded for the VPN server as well.</description></item></channel></rss>